偷天换日
你好!
Hello.
你好，宝贝!
Hello,sweetie.
爸爸
Daddy.
还早着呢!
It's early.
我知道
Yeah,I know.
我想告诉你我给你寄了点东西
I just wanted to let you know I'm sending you something.
是不是很好闻的东西？
Mmm. Does it smell nice?
不是,是闪闪发光的东西
No, but it's sparkly.
有没有收据？
Does it have a receipt?
我在商店直接寄给你的
I'm sending it to you from the store.
你不如来我这里吧！ 我们一起吃早餐
Why don't you just come by? We'll have some breakfast,hmm?
我离你可远了
Well,it'd be a long trip.
我在威尼斯
I'm in Venice.
应该得到了假释官的批准吧？
With your parole officer's approval,of course.
那家伙我喜欢,你知道的
Well,I like the guy,Stella, you know that,
不过我们从没联系过
but we never really connected.
他最后一次造访，我已经把帐单付清了
So I think I've paid my P.O. his last visit.
你要干什么？爸爸？
What are you into,Dad?
你别伤了我的心 你说过你已经金盆洗手了
Don't break my heart. You told me you were through.
干完这次就收山，我对你发誓！
After this I am,I swear to you.
查理在吗？
Is Charlie there?
我用手机打的电话
I'm on a cell phone,darling.
明天我会用有线打给你
I'll call you tomorrow from a land line.
我爱你！ 继续睡吧，再见！
I love you. Go back to sleep. Bye.
爸爸？
D... Dad?
我也爱你
I love you,too.
东西我寄了
I sent it.
要逛衔应该等到大功告成之后
You're supposed to do your shopping after we pull off the job.
我很有信心 怎么说？
I feel so optimistic. So?
你感觉如何？ 很好！
How do you feel? I'm fine.
很好？
Fine?
你知道“好”代表什么吗？
You know what "fine" stands for,don't you?
很遗憾，我知道
Yeah,unfortunately.
兴奋过度
"Freaked out."
“不可靠” －“神经质”
"lnsecure." "Neurotic."
还有“情绪化” －对
And "Emotional." Good.
看见你身后那些柱子吗？
See those columns behind you?
怎么了？
What about them?
是用来绑那些自我感觉很“好”的贼
That's where they used to string up thieves who felt "fine."
你也跑不掉
Well... after you.
得手之后再吸
For after the haul.
希望有机会享受
Hope I get to fire it up.
收垃圾的还没消息？ 没有
Still no word from the garbagemen? No.
如果他们不出现...
If they're no-shows,
我们三个月的准备就付诸东流
three months of prep down the tubes
我也白劝阻你退休了
and I dragged you out of retirement for nothing.
这样真有趣，我喜欢
Oh,this is fun. I like this.
你来负责，别患得患失
You've taken over the reins, all the worries.
我可以轻松自在，逍遥上路
Me loosey-goosey, just along for the ride.
好高兴你能自得其乐，约翰
I'm glad you're enjoying yourself,John.
记住，警察乘船赶到要7分钟
Just remember,a police boat can get from the station to our position in seven.
也就是说只有4分钟给你施展身手
That means you got four minutes to work your magic.
你以前说是10分钟 这会又说5分钟
Now,you told me ten, and you said I would have five.
什么时候说的？
When?
你别搞得我一头雾水好吗? 我会扁你的
Do not be messing with me right now,okay? I will kick your ass.
是吗？
Oh,yeah?
来啊，放马过来吧！ 来吧！
Come on,take your best shot. Come on.
什么？
What? Uh-oh.
来吧   快点！
Come on. Let's go.
你在看什么书？ 达・芬奇
What is it this time? Da Vinci.
建筑家，机械专家，画家 真吸引人
Architect.Engineer. Painter.Yeah,fascinating.
嘿,嘿,你注意听听这句话书名
Hey,look,look. Check this out.
“象达・芬奇一样思考”
"Learn the language of poetry, art,romance,sex."
老友，我可不象你，还需要什么人生指南！
Unlike you,my friend, I don't need a guidebook.
能走了吗？拜托！ 遵命，老大！
Can we go? Please? Right,guv'nor.
快来干点活 把绳子松开
Come along, make yourself useful. Untie that line.
今天 对
Today. Yeah
是的，纪立根,如果你不介意的话
Yeah. Yeah,Gilligan. If you don't mind.
准备好了？ 好了
We set? -Yeah. I've enhanced
增强的电脑模型…
the viewing matrix
可以追踪目标的坐标及三个方向的高度
to track both the Cartesian coordinates and three altitude angles,
可以偏离，倾斜，旋转…
the yaw,pitch and roll to give us
以取得目标的准确方位值
the exact position and orientation of our baby.
我们是在意大利 请说英语
We're in ltaly. Speak English.
史蒂夫，情况如何？
Steve,how we looking?
父亲在8点15乘船出去工作，所以船库会空出来
Papa took the boat to work at 8:. 1 5,so the garage is empty.
母亲象往常一样在8点半送女儿上幼儿园
Mama left with daughter at 8:.30 for preschool as usual.
45分钟内
So for the next 45 minutes,
这个地方属于我们的,先生们
we own this place,gentlemen.
收垃圾的还没有消息吗？
Still no word from the garbagemen?
嘿,你怎么变得这么婆婆妈妈
Hey,who got you the beekeepers in Budapest?
他们会出现的 你应该信任这帮人
They'll be there. You can trust these guys.
史蒂夫，我和你说过多少次了？
Steve,how many times do I have to tell you?
我什么人都信任，只是不信任内心的邪恶
I trust everyone-- I just don't trust the devil inside them.
我们到了
We're in.
告诉我在哪涂
Just tell me where to paint.
你的人还没就位？ 他们会就位的
Your men are still not in position? They will be.
你不能肯定，史蒂夫 我们要中止计划
Well,you don't know that, Steve. We should abort.
对不起！ 我认为该由查理来作主
I'm sorry,John,but I think that's Charlie's call now.
宝贝今晚就要运离这里 现在是我们唯一的机会
Our baby's being taken out of here tonight. This is our only shot at it.
查理？
Charlie?
继续？
Keep going?
你拿主意
It's up to you,kid.
干吧
It's a go.
好了，史蒂夫
Okay,Steve.
离西墙14尺8英寸
From the west wall, measure 1 4 feet,eight inches.
搞定
Got it.
离北墙8尺5英寸
Now measure eight feet,five inches from the north wall.
就是宝贝的位置
That's the northwest corner of our baby.
搞定
Got it.
好了，就在你正上方
Well,it's right above you.
开始涂吧
Now,paint.
2尺9英寸宽
Two feet,nine inches wide.
2尺5英寸长
Two feet,five inches deep.
好了，左耳，该你了
Okay,Left Ear. You're up.
离西墙14尺4英寸
1 4 feet four inches from that west wall.
喂
Yeah.
好运
Bene,
收垃圾的已就位，约翰
The garbagemen are in position,John.
保险箱在船上
好的，查理 有人报警了
All right,Charlie, someone just called it in.
警察正向你方赶来
The police boat's heading your way.
7分钟计时 动手吧
Seven minutes and counting. Let's go.
4分钟时间装货，动手吧
We got four minutes to load and leave. Let's go.
Whoa!  Whoa!
嘿，小伙子们，过来这里
Hey,you guys. Come here.
我提议碰一碰
I want to propose a toast.
为我们
To us.
Yay!
然后再为查理喝一口
And I want to propose a toast to Charlie
不发一枪就到手 价值3500万的金子
because we just stole $35 million worth of gold
全归功于他计划周详
without even holding a gun because he planned this down to a "T '."
这点没人做得到 没人
Nobody else could have done that.
查理！ 查理
Nobody. Charlie! Charlie! -Yay!
谢谢
Thank you.
来吧，先生吧
So,come on,gentlemen.
计划一下购物清单和活动 可以花个痛快了
Shopping list. Who's doing what? Spare no dirty details.
算了吧，小伙子
Come on,you guys.
听老汉一言
T ake a lesson from an old man.
钱不要乱花，去投资
Don't spend it. Invest.
投资什么？
In what?
投资到金子上
In gold.
还是先考虑 如何离开这里吧
Let's figure out how to get out of here first, all right?
你打算买什么？
What are you getting,Rob?
我不知道，好多东西想买 －你可以手握巨款疯狂购物
I don't know-- there's a lot of things you can buy with a lot of money.
现在，我正幻想拥抱着真皮椅上的裸女
You know,I'm just thinking about naked girls in leather seats.
看得出来
Obviously. See?
来部阿斯顿・马汀如何？
Suppose I get the Aston Martin Vanquish?
没多少女孩不愿意坐在这种车上
There's not a lot a girl won't do on the passenger seat of one of those things.
我要买一套NADT770功放
I'm going to get a NAD T770
70瓦功率 使用伯尔布朗芯片
I'm going to get a NAD T770 digital decoder with a 70-watt amp and Burr Brown DACs.
这可是功率巨大的系统
Yeah. It's a big stereo.
喇叭声大到可以 帮女人宽衣解带
Speakers so loud they blow women's clothes off.
终于露出庐山真面
Now you're talking.
3千5百万啊 不能花得有点创意吗？
$35 million-- you can't get more creative than that,man?
我要去安达鲁西亚 西班牙南部，就在那边...
I'm going to Andalucia, south of Spain... right there.
买一幢豪宅
Get me a big house...
搞个收藏首版书的图书馆
get me a library full of first editions.
辟个房间 专门放我的鞋
Get a room for my shoes.
你呢，史蒂夫？
What about you,Steve?
不知道，还没有想好
I don't know-- I haven't decided yet.
还没想好了？
You haven't decided yet?
少来了 是不是因为高山缺氧，还是…？
Come on,man, is it the mountain air,just...?
我要博取众长 大家的建议都会采纳一些
I liked what you said. I'll take one of each of yours.
多采纳一些 为史蒂夫
Well,well,two of everything for Steve then. -Two of those. Oy!
还在回味吗
Loved the toast.
你闭着眼也能把保险箱搞定
But you could've pulled this off with your eyes closed.
不，你表现的 令人不可思议
No,you were incredible.
不可思议
Just incredible.
你计划周密 纵观全局
You saw the whole picture. You covered all the angles.
你知道的，查理...
You know,Charlie,
在这个世界上有两种贼：
there are two kinds of thieves in this world:
一种是为钱而偷...
the ones who steal to enrich their lives,
一种是为偷而偷
and the ones who steal to define their lives.
别成为后者
Don't be the latter.
这样会使你忽略人生要义
Makes you miss out on what's really important in this life.
你是什么意思，约翰？
What are you talking about, John?
你是个好父亲
You've been a good father.
身陷囹囵可成不了慈父
Sitting in prisons doesn't make you a good father.
女儿出生后 我有一半时间在牢里渡过
I spent half my kid's life in prison.
到我这把年纪 你可别象我这样,查理
Don't get to be my age with nothing but this,Charlie.
去寻找可与你共渡余生的人
Find somebody you want to spend the rest of your life with
并与她一生相守
and hold onto her forever.
好吧？
Okay?
嘿
Hey.
走吧，我都快冻僵了
Let's go-- I'm freezing my ass off.
好的
Yeah.
史蒂夫怕冷 你也是？
Steve's getting cold. You,too?
我没事
I'm all right.
我爱你，孩子
I love you,kid.You did really great.
多谢，约翰
Thanks,John.
走吧
Let's go.
*Money
*It's a gas
*Grab that cash with both hands and make a stash
*New car,caviar, four-star daydream...
可惜你们没看到 罗布开船的英姿
You should've seen Rob behind the wheel of that boat.
就象唐强森一样
He was like Don Johnson.
是，从布瑞克顿来
Oy,yeah,from Brixton.
你知道布瑞克顿？
Yeah,what the hell do you know about Brixton,eh?
路中间那傻车怎么开的
Look at this idiot right in the middle of the road.
怎么回事？怎么回事？
What's this,what's this?
这是帮什么人？
Who the hell are these guys?
嘿 把手从方向盘拿开
Hey!Take your hands off the wheel.
史蒂夫
Steve!
不要搞什么花样
Don't even think about it-- just do it.
不，不
No,no,
史蒂夫 你在搞什么鬼？
no,no,no,no,John. -Steve, what the hell are you doing?
实施我个人的一些计划
Made a few plans of my own.
你上天入地我们都会把你挖出来 史蒂夫，你知道的！
There's nowhere you can go where we won't find you,Steve. You know that.
你说得对极了,约翰
I think that's probably right, John.
快开，快开
Go! Go!
查理
Charlie.
我们得走了，查理
We got to go,Charlie.
一年以后，费城
你怎么老是摸黑工作？
You always work in the dark?
让我有种孤独感
Makes me feel like I'm alone.
不错 不错，斯特拉
Not bad. Not bad,Stella.
赫利没法打开这个保险箱
Damn. Hurley couldn't crack that safe.
斯皮尔也不行
Neither could Spears. Now you know
现在你知道该找谁了吧
who to call first.
你收费太高了，斯特拉 上头削减我们的经费用于...
You're expensive,Stella. Those guys cut us a break on subpoena jobs.
传讯及感化服务
Good will,community service.
我工作是为了钱，保罗我会把帐单寄给你
I do it for the money,Paul. I'll be sending you a bill.
不想看看里面有什么？ 我从来不看里面
Don't you want to see what's inside? I never look inside.
祝你好运
Have a good day. Hey,George.
你好，乔治 你好，斯特拉
Hi,Stella.
*I came,I saw,I kicked some ass*
*The pain I cause, it makes me laugh
*Cause the way I do my thing is strange
*Time,time for this girl to sing
*Damn if I thought that you would change
*And my life would stay the same
*Things will come and things will go
*And one thing I know for sure
*Is that the wreckoning, the wreckoning,the wreckoning
*I'm walking out the door
*Wreckoning,the wreckoning, the wreckoning
*Oh,it's time...
开锁用了多长时间？ 4分43秒
How long to crack it? Four minutes and 43 seconds.
噢！你真厉害
Oh! You're the man.
都有此什么事要我处理？ 托德打来电话
What's on the lineup? Todd Milliken called.
他手头有一把号码锁的原型 他想要你去校验
He has a prototype combination lock. He wants you to test out.
他说他在锁的制栓上附加了两个假的接触点
He says he added two false contact points on the tumbler.
我得假装被难住了 让他高兴一下
I'll pretend to be stumped for a couple of seconds, give him a thrill.
有位查理・科罗克先生在你办公室
And,there's a Charlie Croker in your office.
他说你们认识
Says you two know each other.
查理・科罗克
Charlie Croker.
你好，斯特拉
Hey,Stella.
难道我没告诉你 我不想再见到你
Didn't I tell you I never want to see you again?
你告诉我是你让父亲最后一次出手
I think it was when you told me how my father died,
然后他在你眼皮底下死去的时候
right in front of your eyes, after you pulled him in for one last job.
我们找到他了，斯特拉
We found him,Stella.
他在洛杉矶
He's in Los Angeles.
他从我们这偷走的金砖上刻着巴厘岛舞娘女
The gold bricks he stole from us had a Balinese dancer stamped on them.
我从一个叫斯吉尼・皮特 的朋友那收到风
I just got word, from a contact of mine called Skinny Pete,
洛杉矶有个大买家 正在吃进这批金砖
that a gold dealer out in L.A. has been buying those bricks.
是吗？
Yeah?
好，你怎么知道是他？
Well,how do you know it's him?
斯吉尼・皮特给我的
Skinny Pete sent me this.
史蒂夫把姓改为弗拉泽利
Steve changed his last name to Frazelli.
你告诉我这些做什么？
Why you telling me all of this?
我查了安全 保卫公司的数据库
Been checking out the databases behind safe companies.
发现有一套渥新顿1000系统
Found out Steve had a Worthington 1000
寄到史蒂夫的公司
delivered to his home office.
你没有安装Worthington 1000
You don't install a Worthington 1000
除非你有重要的东西需要保管
unless you've got something really big to guard.
不，你没有
No,you don't.
问题是我们无法对付史蒂夫这套安全系统
The problem now is no one in my crew can handle Steve's safe.
而我需要一些足以信赖的人
And I need somebody I can trust.
我是保险箱及保险库的技术专家 我可不是贼
Look,I'm a professional safe and vault technician. I'm not a thief.
不只是为了金子，斯特拉
Hey,it's not about the gold, Stella,okay?
约翰我也视之如父
John was like a father to me,too.
对不起
Look,I'm sorry,all right?
此仇不报我无法释怀
I just can't move on until I've set things right.
我已经释怀了
I've moved on.
来吧，查理
Come on,Charlie.
来吧
Come on.
你好
Hello?
我想看看那人两手空空的样子
I want to see the look on that man's face when his gold is gone.
他害死了我父亲 我要报仇
He took my father from me:, I'm taking this.
她要出手了
She's in.
算是好事吗？ 非常好的事
That's a good thing? It's a very good thing.
她可以干净利索地破解渥新顿1000
She can crack a Worthington 1000 without even flinching.
一位守法公民加入我们 不一定是好事
I'm not sure having a civilian on the crew's a good idea,Charlie.
她有技术也有动机
She's got the skill and she's got the motivation.
没错
Exactly.
她也很情绪化
She's emotional.
你知道掺入个人情绪是什么结果
You know what happens when emotion gets into it.
别自欺欺人了
Look,don't kid yourself, all right?
我们都带着情绪
We're all emotional on this one.
来吧
Let's go.
准备好没有？ 当然
Are you ready? Of course I am.
没准备好
You're not ready.
好快
That was quick.
他们呢？
Where are they?
我们来早了点 我没想到这么快到
We're a little early. I didn't expect us to get here quite that fast.
那里 莱尔来了
There. That's Lyle.
他是个电脑天才
He's my computer genius.
他是Napster（著名音乐共享软件） 真正作者
You know,he's who really invented Napster.
至少莱尔是这么说的
At least that's how Lyle tells it.
他说芬宁（Napster作者）是他的室友 把他的创意给偷了
Said Shawn Fanning was his roommate in college and stole his idea.
他第一次骑那部摩托
Think it's his first time riding that bike,though.
嘿
Hey.
Oh...
没事吧？
You okay?
没事
Yeah. Mm-hmm.
那是左耳
That's Left Ear.
爆破专家
Demolition and explosives.
10岁的时候在马桶里放了太多M80 结果爆炸了
When he was ten, he put one too many M-80s in the toilet bowl.
Fire...
真酷
Whoa.Yeah,that was cool.
怎么做到的？
How'd you do that?
什么？
What?!
你怎么做到的？
How'd you do that?
什么？
What?!
我说，你怎么做到的？
I said, how did you do that?
什么？
What?!
他右耳因此丧失听力
Lost the hearing in his right ear.
从那以后他就开始东炸西爆
He's been blowing stuff up ever since.
大帅哥罗布 超级车手
Handsome Rob. Premier wheel man.
有一次曾经跑遍洛杉矶所有的路
Once drove all the way from Los Angeles
只是为了创造最长追车记录
just so he could set the record for longest freeway chase. You're a heartbreaker...
他在监狱里收到110封求爱信
You know,he got 110 love letters sent to his jail cell
全是电视上对他 一见钟情的女人写的
from women who saw him on the news?
*You're a heartbreaker
*Dream-maker
*Love-taker
*Don't you mess around, no,no,no...
你呢？
And you?
那你的经历呢？
I never heard how you got your start.
我？
Me?
我乳臭未干就是个小贼
Well,I've been a thief since I had baby teeth.
好了，你们俩都知道怎么做了
Okay,you both know what to do.
交出来
Cough it up,now!
Come on,now, shake it,shake it,baby,ho!
One,two,three,baby...
看着，笨蛋！
Watch it,spaz!
Hey,now,do,re,me,baby...
嘿，你想干吗，小子？
Hey,what's your problem,man?
A-B-C,it's easy
As one,two,three...
嘿，查理 见到你很高兴，伙计
Hey,Charlie. Good to see you,man.
气色不错 是吗？
Looking good. -Yeah?
查理・哈斯特 见到你很高兴
Charlie Hustle. -Good to see you.
你好，查理 罗布，还好吗？
Hello,Charlie. Rob,what's up? Good?
兄弟们,斯特拉・布里捷
Guys... Stella Bridger.
嗨
Hi.
你好 见到你很高兴
How you doing? Nice to meet you.
电话呢？
Phones?
电话全是新的 这里是内部的芯片
Yeah,they're all fresh and clean, I got internal chips in them.
请每天更换两次
Please change them twice a day. We will get heat on line.
身份证呢？
I.D.S?
詹姆斯・黑曼？
"James Hymen?"
别这样，哥们 给我个好名字
Come on,man,one time, give me a cool name.
140磅？还不如写165
140 pounds? Try 165.
你增加点体重吧
Try lifting some weights.
好了，伙计们 我们明天出发，是吗？
Try lifting up these. -Guys,enough. Come on,we leave tomorrow,all right?
走吧
Let's go.
嘿，查理…
Hey,Charlie...
帅哥，帮他整整那部摩托
Handsome,can you help him with the bike?
好的，为他再摔一次作准备
Yeah,help Knievel set up for his next jump.
*Like a sound you hear that lingers in your ear
*But you can't forget, from sundown to sunset
*No,no
*It puts a brand-new kind of thinkin' in your mind
*And you can't go wrong
*Cause you're groovin' all day long,ha-ha!
*California soul
*Ooh-ooh-ooh
*California soul...
世上这么多藏身之地中
Man,out of all of the places for a thief to hide,
这个家伙选中了好莱坞
this joker picked Hollywood.
他是个混蛋 不过还有点脑子
He's a punk, but he ain't stupid.
好了
All right...
我们得想办法 进入史蒂夫的家中
we need to figure out a way to get in Steve's house
拍个内部结构图的摄像
and make a video blueprint of the interior.
我要监听他的电话
I want audio surveillance on his phone.
好，我来想想办法
Oh,yeah,I been wanting to try something.
我侵入电话公司的 远程监控系统
I crack into the phone company's remote monitoring system,
做些手脚使系统认为 对某线路的监听合法
and fool it into thinking there's a legal tap on the line.
将话音转接到我们 自己的监听电话上
Just reroute the digital copies of the calls to our own listening post.
我监听过我前妻好几年？
I been doing it to my ex for years.
多长时间？
How long?
是问你办成 需要多长时间
No-- how long will it take?
不是问你监听了 老婆电话多长时间？
Not how long have you been doing it to your ex.
熬个通宵 应该早上就可以了
I'll burn through the night; I'll have it running by morning.
对不起，我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
我们要设法 让史蒂夫走出家门
We got to work on getting Steve out of the house.
斯特拉，破解渥新顿需要多长时间？
Stella,how much time you need with the Worthington?
5分钟足已 别太自负了，小妞
Five minutes flat. Don't be cocky,young lady.
这可不是替警察打开个保险箱
It's not the same as opening a safe for the police.
你的手会紧张得冒汗 心会砰砰乱跳
The perspiration on your fingertips,your heart's pounding in your ears...
完全是两码事
whole different ball game.
多谢你的关心，我行的
I appreciate your concern. I'll be fine.
大家记住了 上面所说是最容易的行动
Look,just remember, this is all the easy part,okay?
我们最可能失手的地方 就是在逃跑过程中
It's the getaway that can get us caught.
说说计划 我们开车到联合车站
So what's the sketch? We drive to Union Station.
连车一起乘上火车
Getaway car goes right onto the train with us.
我们要知道从史蒂夫家到联合车站的准确时间
We need to know exactly how long it's going to take to get from Steve's house to Union Station.
联合车站 1/2英里
好极了 卡森安全系统
Oh,great.Carson Security System.
性能如何？
How good is it?
卡森公司每年 举办一次竞赛
Carson's held an annual contest--
通过此系统者可获5万美金
$50,000 to anybody that can bypass the system.
挑战者络绎不绝
The Who's Who of ex-cons always show up.
比赛连办5年 没人拿到过那笔钱
Five years running, no one's been paid.
好，各位 我描述这里的情况
Okay,party people, here's the status.
不锈钢栅栏
It's an anti-scaling fence.
坚硬电镀钢条所制
It's hardened, electro-plated steel.
我会把盐酸氮芥 涂到栅栏上的
Yeah,I'm going to have to paint that up with some nitromin.
房子的警卫情况？ 一名携枪警卫
Security on the property? Got an armed guard here.
花钱雇来的 屁股后一把9MM口径手枪
Little rent-a-cop, with a nine-millimeter on his hip.
不过那个保安亭…
But that booth...
保安亭很合 麻醉手榴弹的胃口
Security booth looks prime for a chemical grenade.
盐酸氮芥麻醉手榴弹 这些东西不容易搞到
Nitromin,chemical grenades... I mean,that stuff's pretty hard to come by.
对，莱尔,有价无市
Yeah,Lyle,it's a bear market.
妈的
Shit.
这公子哥居然养了狗
This dude got dogs.
狗我可应付不来 我曾有过惨痛经历
I don't do dogs. I had a... real bad experience,man.
怎么了？ 我有过惨痛经历
What happened? I had a bad experience.
该死，我聋了
Damn it. I'm deaf.
本年吸烟致死人数统计
交出你的徽章和武器 哦，妈的
You turn in your badge and your weap... Oh,shoot.
"交出你的徽章和武器"
Turn in your badge and your weapon!
捏死你
Crush.
这桩案子里我不想见到你出现
I don't want to see you anywhere near this investigation.
交出你的徽章和武器
And turn in your badge and your weapon.
这桩案子里 我不想见到你出现
I don't want to see you anywhere near this investigation.
嘿！绿灯了
Hey! It's a green!
交出你的徽章和武器
Turn in your badge and your weapon.
绿灯
Green!
我不想见到你出现…
-I don't want to see you anywhere near this...
交出你的徽章和武器
Turn in your badge and your weapon.
真不敢相信
Unbelievable.
他现身了
There he is.
干活吧
Let's get to work.
到处都是堵车塞车
It's either bad traffic, peak traffic,
交通瘫痪
slit-your-wrist traffic.
今天有5个人 在交通堵塞期间吸烟致死
You know,five people died from smoking in between traffic lights today.
这里还有地铁，罗布
You know,they do have the Metrorail,Rob.
我们应该乘地铁
You could always use that.
带着一大堆黄金坐地铁 真是个高招，是吧，天才？
That'd be ideal for carrying a ton of gold, wouldn't it,genius?
你预测的时间是多少？
What's your guesstimate?
按我最后20次的时间计算
The last 20 times I've done the journey,
平均32分钟，最长50分钟
you've got an average of 32 minutes and a top time of 50,
如果一路绿灯 14分钟可以到达
but if we had green lights all the way, we could do it in 1 4 minutes.
不堵车有可能吗？
Wait,you couldn't get through traffic?
Whoa.
如果一路绿灯我们就不用担心了
We could do anything with green lights all the way.
莱尔？
Lyle?
我尽力而为吧
I'll see what I can do.
大宗珠宝交易
你很准时
You're right on time.
那些可怜的傻瓜
All these poor bastards out there,
把全付身家都放在银行和共有基金里
putting their life savings in banks, and S&Ls,and mutual funds.
不知道他们怎么想的银行倒闭的时候
How do they think, when the collapse comes,
难道政府指望得上吗？
they can depend on the government?
我可不觉得
I don't think so.
你把我录下来了？ 当然不会
Are you taping me? Of course not.
我从来没录过你，过来看 你自己看
I never tape you-- come look, see for yourself.
政府只是个傀儡而已
Governments are nothing more than puppets and strings
北美贸易协会 可以支配最高法院
in a world where NAFTA can overrule the Supreme Court.
就象我表弟口头禅 这才是我们的庇护神，宝贝
Like my cousin Mashkov always says: "This is our only refuge,baby--
金子
gold."
每次我看着这些雕刻
Every time I look at these engravings...
总觉得是如此美丽
She's so beautiful.
你说你从哪搞来的？ 我没说过
Where'd you say you got these? I didn't.
一点黑金
A little walking around money.
数目和我想象的不一样
I guess I'm not walking as far as I thought.
很抱歉 今天我只能买两条
I'm... sorry. I can only buy two bricks from you today.
协议可不是这样的
That wasn't the agreement.
我能怎么办？ 我只是个中间人
What can I say?I'm just middleman.
星期三我会买下另外两条
I'll buy the other two from you on Wednesday.
别浪费我的时间
Don't waste my time,Yevhen.
身家3千5百万的男人 晚上会干什么？
So,what does a man with 35 million dollars worth of gold do at night?
不过看个狗屁大电视
He watches his big-ass TV.
该干活了
That's our in.
斯特拉 天啊
Stella. Jesus!
查理！
Charlie!
你怎么进来的？ 我敲了门，你没回答
How did you get in here? I knocked, but you didn't answer.
所以你就闯进来了？ 我只是担心你的安全
What-- so you just let yourself in? I was just making sure you were okay.
我道歉，我...
I apologize. I just...
别看
l... -Don't look.
好了
Okay.
You got a lot of stuff here.
好了
令尊是个守旧派 全凭触觉干活
You know, your dad was old school. Did the whole thing by touch.
蛇有蛇路 鼠有鼠道
That worked for him; this works for me.
技术可以保证速度和精确
T echnology guarantees speed and accuracy,you know?
我们干的事可没什么保证,斯特拉
Yeah,but there's no guarantees in this business,Stella.
耳机用来作什么？
Why the headphones?
只是用于自我训练
Just training myself.
环境噪声，为了以防万一
Ambient noises,you know, just in case.
你有什么事吗？查理
What do you want,Charlie?
我们会破坏史蒂夫家中的电缆 然后派个修理工进去
We're going to knock out Steve's cable, and we need to send in a repairman.
拍下内部结构的摄像
To get your video blueprint of the interior.
没错
Yep.
问题是史蒂夫 以为我们都死了
Only problem is Steve thinks we're all dead.
除了我
Except me.
我来干吧，查理
I'll do it,Charlie.
我会想方设法办到的
I'm in all the way, whatever it takes.
好吧，我会安排好的
All right. I'll set it up.
好的
Okay.
嗯，你……嗯…… 想不想出去喝杯饮料？
Um... you,um... maybe want to get a drink downstairs with me
在睡觉之前
before I go back to my room?
我得把事干完
I sh... I should finish this stuff up,you know?
今天要把这些都弄好 好的
Just get it all done tonight. Yeah.
吓着你真对不起 没关系
Sorry I scared you. It's okay.
晚安
Good night.
再见
Bye.
他是媒体的宠儿
And then he's just... the media darling.
上了所有杂志的封面
He's on the cover of all the magazines.
我也应该上 杂志的封面
I should've been on the cover of Wired Magazine.
你知道他怎么说的？
You know what he said?
他说是他命名为Napster 这是他的绰号
He said he... he named it Napster because it-it was his nickname,
由来是戴帽子时 露出的卷发
'cause of the nappy hair under the hat,
明明是因为他 偷东西时我在打盹
but he... it's 'cause I was napping when he stole it from me!
他连业都没毕
He didn't even graduate.
你该把这事忘记了
I think it's time to move on, don't you?
他的公司也关闭了 我希望你的嘴也一起关闭
They shut him down. I wish they'd do the same to you.
有活干了
Here... here we go.Cable chick.
碧奇 好名字
Becky.Nice name...
不知道她怎么称呼其他人
I wonder what she calls the other one.
你没有女朋友真的好奇怪 莱尔
And it's such a mystery why you don't have a girlfriend,Lyle.
我们需要一部 这样的设备车
So,all we need is a... service truck like that one,
一件这样的工作服
a work shirt like hers.
你觉得斯特拉能成功吗？ 我也拿不准
You think Stella can pull it off? I have my doubts.
我没和查理谈过
There's no talking to Charlie,though.
你认为...
You think he's...
寓工作于娱乐之中
mixing business with pleasure?
这事他自己才清楚 我只管干好我的活
He should know better. Only I'm allowed to do that.
好的 你要去哪里？
Right. Where you going?
搞件工作服和一部设备车
To get a work shirt and a service truck.
你不是耍我吧？
Are you kidding me?
他打算怎么办？
How does he do that?
看你怎么办 你在说什么？
How do you do that? What are you saying?
嗨，你好吗？
Hey,how are you?
噢,我很好
Oh,good. I'm good.
幸会，我是罗大帅哥
Nice to meet you, I'm... Handsome Rob.
你叫…？
And you are...?
噢,我叫... 我叫碧奇 我的制服上写着
Oh,my name's... my name's Becky, but it's written on my shirt.
听着,我需要你的制服和车子
Listen,I'm going to need your shirt... and your truck.
好啊，我双手奉上
Perfect. I'll give them both to you.
要不要连我的处女宝一起拿去？
Would you... would you like my virginity as well?
菜单上有吗？
If it's on the menu.
你好幽默啊 你怎么不利用我呢？
Ha,ha,ha,ha, oh,you're so witty. Why don't you take advantage of me?
你不是很聪明，对吧？
Yeah,you're not too bright,are you?
是的
No.
太好了
Perfect.
有什么可以效劳，弗拉泽利先生？ 线路不通了
What can I do for you, Mr. Frazelli? The cable's out.
电视，调制解调器 所有设备都出问题了
The TV,the modem,everything.
快找人过来 让他们动作快点
Now,get somebody up here, and tell them to hurry up.
网通公司，有什么可以效劳？ 嗨,我是东大道3320
Netcom Cable, how can I help you? Hi,I'm up at 3320 East Skyway, and the cable's
我这里线路不通
just gone out-- our modem,everything.
好的，先生，我看看 周四九点到三点之间...
Okay,um,let's see,sir. I have a Thursday between 9::00 and 3:00
如果方便的话我们派人去检查 －好的，谢谢
if that would be good. That's going to work. Thank you.
警卫刚打电话给线路公司
Guard just called the cable company.
约在几点？
What time's the appointment?
周四九点至三点
Thursday between 9::00 and 3:00.
你好
Hello?
嗨,我是网通公司 我知道你们的线路断了
Hi,I'm calling from Netcom Cable. I understand your service is out,
原来安排在周四上门
and there was an appointment set up for Thursday.
是的 我们有位技术员...
Yes.Well,we have a technician working
刚完成任务,就在你们附近
in your area who's finished with an appointment
完成时间比预期要早
earlier than expected.
你们那有人在吗？
Will somebody be there for the next hour?
有人，太好了
Sure,that'd be great.
好的，我们的技术员会过去的
All right,our technician will see you then. Have a nice day.
这是你需要的文件
Here's all the paperwork you need.
让他在下面签上名字和日期即可
Just get him to sign and date at the bottom.
检查一下摄像机
Let's check out the camera.
斯特拉，今天你是英雄
Stella, you'll be going patriotic today.
走路要慢一点 否则图象就会抖动
Make sure you walk slowly,or the image will streak.
Ow. -Ooh.
对不起 没关系
I'm sorry. -It's okay.
不好意思，毕业舞会的时候 我也别不上
Sorry... Couldn't pin the corsage on my prom date either.
你参加过毕业舞会？ 那是他表兄
But you had a prom date? It was his cousin.
在厨房，客厅和 卧室都有电缆
There's cable lines in the kitchen, living room,bedroom,
调制解调器在办公室的电脑上
and the cable modem on the computer in the office.
你必须找到办公室的保险箱
You need to locate the safe in the office.
好的
Okay.
我相信你能 勇敢无畏地面对一切
Just want you to know I think you're very brave going in there.
我知道并不容易
I know it won't be easy.
我也是
I second that.
一切都会好的
It's going to be fine.
怎么了？
What?
你知道，好， 是什么意思？
You know what fine stands for?
兴奋过度，不可靠
Freaked Out. Insecure...
神经质，情绪化 神经质，情绪化
Neurotic,and Emotional.
你很了不起
You'll be great.
Yeah.
早晨好 能看看你的证件吗？
Morning. Can I see some l.D.?
多谢你这么快赶来 这是我的职责
Thanks for coming so soon. Hey,that's part of the job.
好了
All right.
阿斯顿・马丁
Aston Martin Vanquish.
这王八蛋把我的车抢走了
Looks like that bastard took my car.
臭狗
Nasty-ass dogs.
嗨
Hey!
放松
Relax,
天啊
Jesus Christ.
下来吧，不会再骚扰你了
Come on, they won't bother you now.
下来吧
Come on.
进屋去
House.
快点走
Go on,get out of here.
没关系，工作中我经常 会遇上各种动物
It's okay, I'm used to running into all sorts of animals on my job.
史蒂夫・弗拉泽利
Steve Frazelli.
碧奇
Becky.
带我看看哪里出了问题 好,没问题。 这边来
Want to show me that problem? Yeah,of course. This way.
你的屋子真不错 是的
You have a really nice house. Yeah.
1922年，瓷砖都没换过
1922.All the original tiles.
院子里的每块石头都是 来自于塞维尔的修道院
Every stone in that courtyard hauled from some monastery in Seville.
这算什么事啊
What a tactic.
修道院？ 修道院被这个杂种侮辱了
Monastery? Monastery for punk-ass creeps.
你好象无动于衷
You don't seem impressed.
不，把一大堆石头 从一个地方搬到另一地方
No,it's just that I don't think lugging a bunch of rocks
我不觉得特别有趣
from one place to another is quite... that interesting.
对我来说没多大意思
You know,it doesn't quite do it for me.
那你觉得什么有意思？
What does do it for you?
电视
Um... TVs?
我有部大电视
I have a monster TV.
可惜现在用不了了
Not working right now,but...
我要帮你 检查一下调制解调器
But you know,I should probably check out the cable modem,you know.
好的，这边来
Yeah? Yeah,right. Over here.
这套系统我花了3万美元
I paid 30 grand to some punk kid to put this system in.
可它却突然罢工了
One day,it just goes out.
我恨不得吊死 装系统的那家伙
I ought to have him strung up.
这边来
Here we go.
那就是我们的宝贝
There's our baby.
We got him.
找到了
Got any,uh,
电缆从这里穿过吗？ 这里没电缆
wiring coming through here?There's no wiring in here.
那是这儿 是
Just right here? Yeah.
看啊，这是我的… 这是我的NADT770
Look at that,that's my... That's my NAD T770. That's...
这是我的音响
That's my stereo.
你的客户一打开门
I bet most of your customers
发现居然是这么一位姑娘
are pretty surprised when they go to open the door
一定都非常惊奇 是的
for the cable man and find you standing there. Oh,yeah.
他在挑逗她
He's hitting on her.
这里没问题 我得去查查电视
There's no problem here. I should maybe just check the TVs.
好的
Okay.
我要宰了这个王八蛋
You know what, end this shit right now.
我要过去宰了这个王八羔子
I'm going to blow this shit right off the mountain right now.
别，别，别
hey,hey,hey.
你用的是AVM处理器 我只用最好的
I see you got the AVM processor. Only the best.
去把插头插上
Check the box.
我要复位系统
I'm just going to... reset your system.
有时可能 是信号堵塞了
Sometimes these things just get jammed up you know?
应该没问题了
That should do it.
修好了吗？
It's fixed?
把电视打开试试
Turn her on,let's see.
动手
Now.
东京证卷交易指数…
Japan's Nikkei index...
太好了
Perfect.
碧奇，对吧？
Becky,huh?
我们以前见过面吗？
Have we met before?
不，我想没见过
No,I don't think so.
你在这里签个字
If you can just sign there.
如果我请你吃晚饭的话
So,if I was to ask you out to dinner...
会不会成为第一个提出 这种要求的客户？
would I be the first one of your customers to ever do that?
上次来的技术员 你也请他吃饭？
What,you asked your last cable repair guy out for a date?
没有，上次那位体重300磅 留着八字胡
No,but the last one was,like,300 pounds, had a handlebar mustache.
不是我喜欢的类型
You know,not really my type.
这不是个好主意
I don't think it's a good idea.
为什么？公司有规定吗？
Why,is that like some,cable company rule?
没有，其实这是我的原则
No,actually,it's just my rule.
我不和陌生人约会 我才认识你5分钟
I don't go out with strange men. I just met you five minutes ago.
那我得时常故意把线路搞坏
So,I guess I have to,like, sabotage my cable,you know,
以便我们有足够的时间熟悉
till we get to know each other well enough.
祝你好运
Have a nice day.
别这样，我保证我会 很有绅士风度
Come on, I'll be a perfect gentleman,I promise.
我甚至连你的 电话号码都没要
I won't even ask you for your phone number.
我只是想认识你 你愿意去哪都成
I'll just... I'll meet you. Anywhere you want to go.
违背你的原则一次吧
Come on,break your rule once.
吃个晚饭而已
It's just dinner.
算是答应吗？
Is that a yes?
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
他碰了我的手
He touched my hand.
他骚扰我
He came on to me.
不过至少我…
Hey,at least l...
制造了一个机会
I created a window of opportunity,right?
他周五晚上一出去我们就动手
When he goes out Friday night, we go in.
等他意识到你于他不利
By the time he realizes you've stood him up,
我们早已带着金子远去
we'll be long gone with that gold.
是的
Yeah.
这次你得好好把牌洗洗
Make sure you shuffle them cards this time,Left.
嗨，莱尔
Hey,Lyle,
前门和保险库的距离是多少？
what's the distance between the front door and the vault?
别趁我转身就耍花招 你这是输红了眼
Don't deal when my back's turned. You've got that loser's paranoia.
莱尔！
Lyle!
叫他Napster他才理，查理
He only answers to The Napster now,Charlie.
不，我不会叫你Napster
No.I'm not calling you The Napster.
为什么？你叫他左耳
Why not,you call him Left Ear.
好的，是的
Well,I am.
叫他帅哥罗布
And him,Handsome Rob.
因为他就是帅哥
Well,that's because he is Handsome Rob.
那你得叫我Napster
Well,you can call me The Napster.
他们也算同时在同一所大学读书
Come on,they were at the same college at the same time.
你为什么要鼓励他？
Why are you encouraging this?
可这是事实
It is a verifiable fact--
他是我的室友 偷走了我的创意
he was my roommate, he stole my ideas.
我才是Napster
I am The Napster.
好了，好了
All right,all right.
前门和保险库之间的距离是多少，Napster？
What is the distance between the front door and the vault,Napster?
想徒手搬运是不可能的
It's farther than you want to carry it.
我们怎么才能把金子从保险库搬到车上？
Yeah,but,so, how do we get the gold from the vault to the getaway car?
走廊是多宽，Napster？
How wide is the hallway... Napster?
6英尺
Six feet.
好的,金子装好了
Okay,you've got your gold.
Whoo!
这些重量车子承受不了
We need more cars to handle the weight.
我需要找人帮忙
Looks like I'm going to need some help with the custom work,too.
我认识一个人精于此道
I know a man for the job.
我修改了一下摄像机
So I modified the camera to include the...
就样我们就能建立高清晰度的电子地图
so we can create really hi-res digital maps.
那是谁？ 罗布的技工朋友
Who's that? Rob's mechanic friend.
你好，查理 你好
Hey,Charlie. -Hey.
查理，这位是扳手 你好，什么事，伙计
Charlie,this is Wrench. Hey,what's up,man?
罗布说你精于此道 我们需要找人帮忙
Rob tells me you got real talent. We need some body work done.
用这些小车运走2700磅的货物
Need to pack up to 2,700 pounds of cargo in these Minis
小车还得有足够的马力
with enough suspension and horsepower
摆脱追踪
to outrun anything chasing us.
2700磅，是什么货物？ 你别管了
2,700 pounds of what? Of whatever.
我可从中获得多少报酬？
So,what do I get out of this mystery deal,man?
10000美元
10,000.
好的
All right.
What comes around...
洛杉矶交通监控及操控中心
非法登陆
嘿，嘿，嘿！
Oh,hey,hey,hey, hey,hey.
还没机会认识一下
We didn't get a chance to meet yet.
扳手
Wrench.
我叫火腿乳酪 噢，好酷
Ham and cheese. Oh. Oh,that's cold.
太酷了
Damn,that's cold. Mmm.
想要一路绿灯吗？ 想要就办得到
You want all greens? 'Cause,ah,'cause you got them.
你怎么能办到？
What have you got?
欢迎来到洛杉矶交通
Welcome to L.A.'s Automated Traffic Surveillance
监控及管理中心
and Control Operations Center.
他们采用特别设计的算法
See,they use video feeds from intersections
根据十字路口采集的视频信号来预测交通状况
and specifically designed algorithms to predict traffic conditions,
进而控制路口的红绿灯信号
and thereby control traffic lights,so all I did was come up with my own
我把我设计的算法篡改进去 我们就能控制交通了
kick-ass algorithm to sneak in, and now we own the place.
你不想演示一下吗？ 我还以为你不会提这种要求
You want to do a dry run?I thought you'd never ask.
看见吗？红灯 绿灯
See,red light? Green light.
戴尼尔森？ 怎么了？
Danielson? -Yeah?
34号区怎么回事？
What's up with Grid 34?
我们查一查
Let's check it out.
嘿,嘿
Hey,hey.
噢，噢，我...
Oh,oops,did l...?
真的很了不起，对吧？
Oops,wow,but it's awesome. Is that not awesome?
能马上改回来吗？ 可以
Can you change it back now? -Yeah.
红绿灯恢复正常
Lights are working fine.
一起小事故
Just an accident.
很好
That's good.
这些是什么？ 不需要的发动机零件
What are those? Unnecessary engine parts.
我拆了除烟装置 车身减重200磅
I lost your smog controls, and 200 pounds of body fat.
你现在有了部好车
You got yourself a sweet ride now,Charlie.
Put the pedal to the metal and I'm off
And never getting lost
Which way will I turn when roads cross?
Press the petal to the metal, little more when it's scary
But one thing for sure, keep my foot on the floor
Put the pedal to the metal and I'm off
And never getting lost
Which way will I turn when roads cross?
Press the petal to the metal, little more when it's scary
But one thing for sure, keep my foot on the floor
Won't stop driving till it's over
Still be cruising when the sun goes down
Put the pedal to the metal and I'm off
And never getting lost
Which way will I turn when roads cross?
Press the petal to the metal, little more when it's scary
But one thing for sure, keep my foot on the floor...
知道我在想什么吗？
You know what I'm thinking about right now?
看看史蒂夫的脸
The look on Steve's face.
你来早了 我很急
You're early. I'm in a hurry.
当然，佛罗里达的选票
Of course,you know that the Florida
是由CIA及黑帮操纵 是吗？
vote rigging was a ClA and mob operation. Is that so?
自从约翰・肯尼迪 靠着父亲帮忙
Yeah,which is not so very different from when your John F. Kennedy
在选举中舞弊以后 情况都大同小异
won a rigged election with the help of his father.
听这话你心里不舒服
You're uncomfortable that I mentioned it.
不是，我只是不想跑两趟
No,Yevhen,I don't like making two trips.
你们这些美国佬
You Americans.
你们爱你们的英雄
You love your heroes.
美国有个哥伦布节吧？
A holiday for Columbus?
他只是走错了路
He makes the wrong turn,
然后把原住民都给消灭了
and wipes out an entire indigenous people.
你知道哥伦布想找什么吗？ 你肯定会告诉我的
And you know what he was looking for? I bet you're going to tell me.
金子 就像在伊莎贝拉女王时代
Gold. Supposedly for Queen lsabella,
如果梅第奇重返意大利
but don't think that the Medicis back in ltaly
他也会参加这行动的
didn't want a part of that action.
意大利要黄金来干什么呢
And what did ltaly need gold for?
为了在威尼斯作长期的奴隶贸易
For the long-distance slave trade based in Venice.
威尼斯 就在那里...
Venice... that's where these bricks...
你刚才说什么？ 什么也没说...没有
You were saying something? Nothing... No...
不,你正说到兴头上 别停下，我很有兴趣
No,you were really on a roll there. Don't stop. I'm interested.
对不起，我有点昏了头 我的英语
Please,I'm confused, my English--
你明白得很
You understand fine.
关于我的金子你都知道些什么？ 不，我不知道
Now what do you know about my gold? No,I don't--
别想着能骗我
Don't you even think about lying to me.
好,好,我听到谣言 发生在威尼斯的一起劫案
Okay, okay,I,I heard a rumor about a heist in Venice.
价值3千5百万美金的金砖
35 million in bricks,
上面刻着巴厘舞娘
with an imprint of a Balinese dancer on them.
你还告诉过谁？ 谁也没告诉
Who have you told? -No one.
你告诉过谁？ 没有，我对天发誓
Who have you told? No one! I swear to God!
对天发誓？
You swear to God?
你疯了？ 我对天发誓
You crazy? I swear to God.
我没有
I didn't!
我应该相信你
Well,then I guess I believe you.
伊万？
Yevhen?
用力轻一点
Let's putt it this time...
推杆，不要打
Putt,not drive.
很好
Very good.
如果你去做的话... 我就知道你行的
If you can just get it, I know you can, I know you can do it. Much better.
我要见斯吉尼・皮特
I'm here to see Skinny Pete.
他在那边 谢谢，伙计
Yeah,he's over there. Thanks,man.
不要盯着眼看 －啊？
Don't stare. -Huh?
不要盯着眼看 他不喜欢别人盯着他看
Don't stare. He doesn't like when people stare at him.
盯着什么？
Stare at what?
好的，做得好
That was good. That was good.
再来一次 我知道你很快会成功的
Try that one,I know you're going to get that one.
很好
That was great.
斯肯尼・皮特 － 查理
Skinny Pete. -Yo,Charlie.
最近怎样？
What's up,man?
How's it going?
关于那些黄金，我猜对了？
So was I right about the gold bricks or what?
噢，我不是来说这的
Oh,I'm not here to talk about that. We need,uh...
我们需要，呃... 一些补给品
some supplies.
宝贝，先去休息一下
Baby,go relax.
宝贝... 去啊
Baby...
去啊
Go relax.
你！
Yo.
你没事吧
Supplies.
怎么了？ 呃...
What's wrong? Huh?
呃......嗯，一些尼特罗明
Uh... um,some,uh, some nitromin,
呃
uh...
一些，呃...
some,uh...
一些尼特罗明,雷管...
some nitromin,primer...
你怎么了？ －啊？
What's wrong? -Huh?
你！
Yo. Uh,nothing.
没什么，我很好
I'm-I'm cool. I'm-I'm great.
呃，我需要一些,呃，大罐的... 尼特罗明，雷管
Uh,I just need some, uh,big can of... Nitromin,primer,
导火线... 对，对
detonating cord... -Right,right.
两个三线化学榴弹和一个引爆器
...two triple-charged chemical grenades and a launcher.
对，就像，呃，像我之前跟你说的一样
Right,like I had,uh, you know,told you... earlier.
好的
All right.
那大概要五千
Cost you about five G's.
成交，准备好给我电话
Done. Call me.
谢谢，兄弟 不好意思
Thanks,man. I'm sorry about that.
好的，兄弟
Uh-Uh,all right,man.
别生气 走吧
Peace. -Come on.
出来
Get out.
那里
There.
万斯有话对你说
Vance has something to tell you.
说话
Go on.
几星期以前
A couple weeks back...
我在你表兄开的店工作
I was working counter at your cousin's shop.
一个人进来询问 那批舞娘金砖的事
A guy come in asking about gold bricks with Balinese dancer on them.
你跟他说什么了
What did you tell him?
我说我见过这些金砖
I told him that I'd seen some bricks.
对不起
I'm sorry.
那人长什么样
What did this man look like?
他有又长又黑的头发...
He had,uh... Iong black hair,
脖子上有一大片纹身
big tattoo on his neck.
他肯定有400磅重
He must have weighed at least 400 pounds.
我知道是谁
I know that guy.
宝贝，自己去玩
Baby,go relax.
你知道我是谁吗
Do you know who I am?
你是马什科夫
You're Mashkov.
没错
That's right.
你去查问过那些舞娘金砖的事
You were asking about gold bricks with a Balinese dancer on them.
告诉我原因
Tell me why.
史蒂夫打电话来 他在餐厅预订了8点的位子
Steve just called to confirm his 8:00 reservation at the Water Grill.
好，我们再复习一次行动计划 迷倒守卫，8点15打开门
Okay,let's go over it one more time. Gas the guards, doors open 8:15.
保险箱8点25打开
Safe popped by 8:25.
8点35装车完毕 8点45离开
Loaded by 8:35, out the door by 8:45.
直奔联合车站
Straight to Union Station.
一路绿灯 其他地方都是红灯
Only green lights on your route. The rest of the city's red.
警察也像其他人一样在塞车
Cops are stuck in the traffic, like everyone else.
火车10点离站 9点30分保证车子全部进入货柜
Train leaves at 10:00. Cars have to be on the carrier by 9:30.
时间完全正确
Timing's got to be dead on.
去准备一下
Let's get ready.
行动吧
Let's get it.
哇,好漂亮的车
Wow,that is a nice car.
对不起，罗布
Sorry,Rob.
他走了，伙计们
Coast is clear,guys.
是时候了，伙计们 成败就在此举
This is it,guys. Moment of truth.
这是怎么回事
What the hell is this?
该死！
Shit!
斯蒂夫的邻居在开派对
Steve's neighbor's throwing a party.
先生，你是来参加贝克的派对的吗 不是
Are you here for the,uh,Baker party,sir? No.
伙计们，今晚我们没法炸门了
We're not blowing any gates tonight,guys.
太多目击者了
Too many witnesses.
斯特拉
Stella.
我知道
I know,I know.
我的约会要迟到了
I'm late for my date.
对，展现你的魅力
Yeah,and you got to be charming.
你要让他再约你出来
You'll need him to ask you out again.
对不起
Sorry.
请不要站在马路上
Let's get out of the street.
真不可想象你竟然这样做了
I really can't imagine you doing that.
什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
你看起来 不像那种喜欢冒险的女孩
Well,you don't really seem like the adventurous type, you know?
别被我的工作服给迷惑了
Don't let the cable uniform, you know,throw you.
我从来不想当然
I wasn't making assumptions.
我倒是知道你有些想法
I've made some assumptions about you.
真的吗？
Oh,really?
然后？
And?
还是等着瞧吧
Well... you're just going to have to wait and see.
为什么要等？ 不如我们马上验证一下
Why wait? Let's get a check.
到我家去吧 不用推断了…
Let's go back to my place. No assumptions...
今晚不行
Not tonight. It's late.
太晚了，我得回家
I should go home.
什么！公司有作息规定吗
What,you have a cable company curfew?
没有，但我有些不好的回忆
No, but I've made some bad calls in the past.
嘿
Hey.
我们得慢慢来，对吗
We should take this maybe a little slower,you know?
这里饭菜可口 我们言谈甚欢
This lovely dinner, sparkling conversation--
你难道还不信任我吗？ 噢，不
you still don't trust me?
我什么人都相信
Oh,I trust everyone.
只是不相信人们心中的邪恶
It's the devil inside them I don't trust.
这话有意思
It's an interesting saying.
你哪里听回来的？
It's charming. Where'd you pick that up?
忘了 真的？
Can't remember. Really?
有个人也说过 一模一样的话
I knew a guy who said it exactly like that.
真的？ 对
Really? Yeah.
这句话我以前 只听他说过
He's the only person I've ever heard say that.He said it all the time.
他老是挂在嘴边 他的名字叫约翰・布里捷
His name was John Bridger.
你抓疼我了
You're hurting my wrist.
他有个女儿和你差不多年纪
He had a daughter and she was about your age.
放开我的手
Let go of my wrist.
我就觉得你们俩有点像
I knew that there was something familiar about you.
知道吗？你跟你老爸一样
You're exactly like your old man,you know that?
从一开始 我也很喜欢他
I liked him,too, right from the start.
直到杀了他那一刻 我都挺喜欢他
I liked him right up until the minute I shot him.
你到底为谁工作？
Who are you working with?
她是我们的人
She's with us.
齐聚一堂
Gang's all here.
比作贼还差的是什么？
You know,the only thing worse than a thief,Bendel?
懦夫
A coward.
你真该见见令尊 向我求饶的样子
Then you should have seen the way your daddy begged for his life.
不值得 把你的猫栓好了
It's not worth it. Put a leash on your cat.
好啊， 斯蒂夫 查理
Hi,Steve. Charlie.
不错，查理 真不错
Not bad,Charlie. Really,not bad.
你可知道我全力控制自己
You have no idea how hard it is for me
没扑过去宰了你有多么困难吗？
not to reach across this table and kill you with my bare hands.
你应该知道
You know better than that, Charlie.
不能感情用事
Can't let emotion into these things.
告诉我，你不是一时冲动
Tell me it wasn't about emotion
你杀了约翰，置我们于死地 算不算感情用事？
when you shot John and left us all for dead.
这和感情无关
That wasn't about emotion.
和一大堆我想要的金子有关
It was about a lot of gold, and I wanted it.
你老认为自己理所应得 不是这样的
Anything you think you deserved,you didn't.
嘿,别跟我谈论是非对错
Hey,don't talk about right and wrong with me,man,
我根本不屑一顾
cause I just don't give a shit.
好吗？
Okay?
你有你的牌 我有我的招
You got your cards, I got my cards,
我们公平竞争 最后我获胜了，明白吗
we made our play, and I came out on top,okay?
如果你还想再较量一把
Now if you want to start the game up again,
我随时奉陪
that's fine with me.
你们到底想玩什么招？
But what,I mean,what is your play here,really?
你们是怎么计划的？
I mean,come on,what do you... what do you think?
首先要拿掉 我的警卫，对吧？
Y-you'll try to take out my guards,right?
你们不知道我有5名警卫
I have five of them that you don't know about.
你们想让莱尔破解系统
You'll try to have Lyle hack the system.
但明天早上我就会把整个系统换掉
I'll change it again tomorrow morning.
最后一步是什么？
What,what,what was y-your final move?
让布里捷的女儿
I mean,you were going to have Bridger's daughter
打开保险箱？
come in and try to crack my safe?
真是非常浪漫写意
I mean,that's... that's very poetic and all,
可惜我见不到
but I just don't see it.
她根本没机会靠近保险箱
I don't think she'll get anywhere near it.
你一点没变，斯蒂夫 总是想着防守
Same old Steve,huh? Always thinking defensively.
所以你永远成不了老大
That's why you're always number two.
你怎么会这么想？ 你缺乏想像力
How do you figure that? You got no imagination.
拿着这么多钱 也不知道怎么花
Couldn't even decide what to do with all that money.
只会买点俗气之极的东西
You had to buy what everybody else wanted.
那你就继续想象吧，好吗
Oh... well,try this on in your imagination,okay?
金子全没了
That gold is already gone.
少放狗屁，史蒂夫 不，真的，我全处理完了
That's bullshit,Steve. No,really,it's over Charlie.
我正在处理最后两块金砖
I'm trying to move the last two bricks.
想不想跟我去看看 那两块烂金砖？
You want to come after me over a couple of lousy bricks?
真的，我请你作客
I mean,really,be my guest.
真的，你的行动 有个糟糕的开场
But you're off to a bad start, you know? 'Cause you just blew the best thing
因为你最厉害的 手段已经失效
you had going for you.
你无法再攻我不备
You just blew the element of surprise.
攻你不备吧？
Surprised?
我说什么时候结束才算结束
It's over when I say it's over.
你没事吧？先生
Are you all right,sir?
你怎么了？
How you doing?
挺好
Good...
我在想…
considering...
我的所作的为都是
considering the fact that I'm doing all of this
为了一个很不了解的人
for a man I barely knew.
知道那些年我的烦恼是什么吗？
You know what bothered me all those years,Charlie?
就是...
It was that,
他给我电话说他他又重操旧业
whenever he'd call me to tell me that he was on some job,
我就知道你正在他身边
I knew you were right there with him.
你一定比我更了解他
You got to know him a lot better than I did.
他和我在一起时间多点
Just 'cause he was around me more doesn't mean
并不代表他心里没你
he wasn't thinking about you all the time.
如果是真的就太好了
Be nice if it was true.
是真的
It is true.
他总是悔恨自己 不是个好父亲
He always regretted not having been a good enough father to you,Stella.
你怎么知道？
How do you know that?
因为是他告诉我的
Because he told me.
你的手怎么了？
What did you do to your hand?
我教训了史蒂夫
I punched Steve.
为什么你能动手我却不可以？
Why do you get to punch him and I don't?
因为你那双手太值钱了
Those hands are way too valuable.
嗨
Hey.
没事了
Okay?
再擦下去什么都被你擦没了
There'll be nothing left of that if you keep rubbing it.
告诉弗拉泽利先生 我们8点去见他
T ell Mr. Frazelli we'll see him at 8:00.
查理！
Charlie!
他正准备逃之夭夭
He's flying the coop.
什么时候？
When?
他的警卫下午4点叫了直升飞机
His security guard called for a private helicopter at 4::00 PM.
5点有部装甲汽车开到他家
There's an armored car service coming to his house at 5::00.
有一架货机8点由洛杉矶国际机场起飞
There is a cargo plane scheduled to depart LAX at 8:00 PM
飞往墨西哥
to Mexico City.
可能他搬动保险箱只是个障眼法
What if he's moving the safe as a diversion?
我们打开之后却是空的金子在其他地方
We crack it,it's empty, the gold's somewhere else.
史蒂夫不可能让金子离开他的眼皮
Steve's not about to let that gold out of his sight. It's going to be in that truck
金子就在那辆卡车上
and he's going to be watching it
他会从直升机上寸步不离地监控着
every step of the way from the helicopter.
所以金子是要搬往墨西哥的
So the gold's headed to Mexico.
谁知道是哪？
Who knows where?
在空中可以改变飞行计划
They could change the flight plan in midair.
慢来，慢来
Slow down,slow down.
对于此事 大家的看法都不妥当
You guys are looking at this the wrong way.
其实我们来说是件好事
This is good news for us.
查理，你什么意思， 好事？
Charlie,what do you mean,"good news"?
我们想方设法要 取得保险箱里的金子
We've been trying to get to the gold in the safe,
现在保险箱就要出现在我们面前
now the safe is coming to us.
我们要在运输途中动手
We're going to boost it in transit.
查理，到机场有很多条路线
Charlie,it could take a dozen different routes to the airport.
我们不知道是哪一条
We have no idea which one.
交通高峰期间我们 对付不了装甲卡车
We can't take out an armored truck during rush hour.
我们已经安排好了
We're already set up to do it.
Napster,
Napster...
封锁其他行车路线 除了我们指定的那条
gridlock every route except for the one we choose.
强迫卡车行进到我们 安排好的位置上
Force that truck to go exactly where we want it to go.
我们要让卡车开到哪里去
Where do we want it to go?
我们没法向武装警卫开枪 我们会失手的
We can't have a shoot-out with armed guards. We'd lose.
我们可以象在意大利那样干
We do it like the ltalian job.
你好 你为什么要这么干？
Hello? Why'd you do it?
干什么？ 伊万
Do what?Yevhen.
你没必要废了他
You didn't have to clip him.
喔，喔，你说什么？ 我们什么人也没废过
Whoa,whoa. What are you talking about? We didn't clip anybody.
伊万的表弟对此 可是深信不疑
Yevhen's cousin is under the distinct impression that you did.
他为什么这么想？
Why does he think that?
因为你对那批刻着舞娘的金块很有兴趣
Because you want to know about the gold with the Balinese dancer.
你告诉他了？ 你听我说，兄弟
You told him that? Listen to me,man.
我给你个忠告 永远别去招惹
If there's one thing that I know is never to mess with Mother Nature,
反复无常的乌克兰人
mother-in-laws or mother-freakin' Ukrainians.
听着，你要帮我一个忙
Look,I need a favor.
喂 昨晚出了点问题
Yeah. Had a hiccup last night.
需要找你作个帮手
Could use some help.Want hands-on this time.
有没有兴趣？ 也许吧
You interested? Could be.
可我不希望暗地里加入 我加入就要成为正式的一份子
But I don't like to be kept in the dark. If I'm in,I'm in.
好的，算你一份
Okay,you're in.
好的
All right.
怎么样，查理？ 没问题，走吧
What do you think,Charlie? This'll work. Let's go.
你真了不起 天才的杰作
You're amazing. It's a work of genius.
Uh-huh.
你没事吧？
You okay?
是的，让我休息一会 现在？
Just give me a moment. Now?
我要把这东西插入雷管里
I'm about to insert this pin into this detonator tube,
如果上面的铜皮碰到雷管
and if the brass touches the sides,
我们就会与世长辞
we'll both be the last people we ever see.
那你愿意休息多久 就休多久吧
T ake all the time you need.
嘿，查理？ 怎么了？
Hey,Charlie. What?
我爱你，伙计
I love you,man.
我也爱你
I love you,too.
好的
Okay.
他会出现在开往 新奥尔良的59次车上
消息来源可靠吗？
绝对可靠
请注意 774次列车 在15分钟后到站
Metrolink train number 774 will arrive in approximately 1 5 minutes.
报告各自位置
Check positions.
Napster？
Napster?
我已经就位
I'm in position.
帅哥罗布？
Handsome Rob?
我们已经就位 周围很安静
We're in position. Everything's quiet,Charlie.
扳手？
Wrench?
布置妥当
Set.
查理，有不速之客
Charlie,we got an uninvited visitor.
卡车后有摩托手押车
Some motorcycle guard following the truck.
我们会安排的
We'll deal with it.
这些车是什么？
Who are these cats?
怎么了？ 查理，真不敢相信
What's wrong? Charlie,you won't believe this.
他叫了三部装甲卡车来
He's brought in three armored trucks.
真真假假的障眼法
It's a shell game. Shell game now.
老大，我不知道是哪部车 可没法控制车的行进路线
Well,boss, I can't reroute the truck if I don't know which truck to reroute.
就是直升机 跟着的那辆车
Just go with the one Steve follows in the helicopter.
记住，他说过永远不会 让金子离开他的视线
Remember,he said he'd never let that gold out of his sight.
除非他耍我们 要不就是那部车
Unless he's playing us, and he is.
好的，出发
Okay,let's go!
动身
Moving out!
来了
Here we go.
他们动身了
They're pulling out.
Napster 移动监控摄像机
Napster, pull up the traffic cameras you're watching.
卡车通过的 第一个路口是哪里？
Where's the first camera the trucks go past?
维恩和加科路口 三部车都会经过那里
Vine and Yucca; they're all going to cross there.
看一下哪部车车身较低
See which one's riding low.
第一部是…
First one is...
第二部也一样，所以…
First two are the same,so...
休斯敦，目标找到，车号128
Houston,we have our truck. It is number 1 28.
我们跟在后面
We're moving out.
三千 呼叫 双狐 我们正前往机场
Three-kilo-bob to two-fox-mike, we're heading to the airport.
好了伙计们 128号车转右向西去了
Okay,guys,truck 1 28 has turned right heading west.
堵塞交通
Gridlock time.
系统崩溃了
We've crashed.
不是崩溃
It's not a crash.
也没有停电
We've got power.
我无法登录
I can't log in.
准备让他们兜个大圈 然后送到门口上来
They are about to hit a major detour and be sent your way.
喔
Oops.
你们…永远无法…关闭…
You'll... never... shut down...
真正的…Napster
the real... Napster.
128号车 你们进展如何？
Truck 1 28, what is your progress?
这里是128号车
This is truck 1 28.
这里交通失控 我们得走另一条路
Traffic's out of control here. We've got to look for another route.
监听警察的通讯
Check the police band.
好的，我给你们开出一条通道
Okay,I'm opening up a space on Highland.
快离开这里 我正在想办法
Oh,get us out of here. I'm trying.
中招了
And he's taking it.
交通管制中心的电脑 崩溃了
Police scanners are saying computers are down at Traffic Control Center.
干得好，查理
Nice,Charlie.
你到底想干什么？ 回头
What are you up to? Go back.
我现在命令你左转
I now command you to turn left.
快点，往左转
Come on,take the left.
听话 真听话
Yeah,you did. You did.
给我们指示
Give us the flag.
地铁刚刚离站 你们有90秒的时间
Metro just passed through the station. You are clear for 90 seconds.
走
Go.
来了，史蒂夫
Come on,Steve.
Whoa,whoa,whoa.
还剩30秒
30 seconds and counting.
还有15秒，不成功便成仁
1 5 seconds, you're either blocked in or you're paint on the train.
快，快
Go,go,come on,come on!
跟紧我
Stay right on me, this is gonna be tight.
快，快，快
Go,go,go,go,go,go!
乘客们到站了
You're gonna stop right there.
好了伙计们
Okay,guys.
他就来了
Coming into position.
冷静
Stay cool.
10... Ten...
9... nine...
8... eight...
7... seven...
6... six...
5... five...
4... four...
别跟丢，别跟丢 别跟丢
Don't lose 'em, don't lose 'em,
3... don't lose them. -three...
2... two...
one.
该死
Damn.
我的车去哪了？
Where's my truck?
我的车出了什么事？
What...? What the fuck happened to my truck?!
街上发生爆炸
It just blew right through the street.
好的，快下去
Well,get under there.
麻烦来了，伙计们 怎么了？
We have another problem,guys. What?
这不是渥新顿1000 什么？
This isn't the Worthington 1000. What?
他换了个保险箱
He switched safes on us.
你能搞定吗？ 以色列出产的
Can you do it? It's lsraeli made.
带有玻璃防盗系统
It's got a glass re-lock system.
门后面是一大块玻璃
There's a pane of glass right here behind this door.
如果钻孔的位置稍有偏差
And if I don't drill perfectly through that hole,
内部的钢条 把门锁死之后
steel rods snap into place and you can't open the safe.
就无法打开保险箱 我们的麻烦可就大了
And then we're up shit creek.
我刚才碰到玻璃了
I think I just cracked the glass.
应该还没碎
I don't think it broke though.
我不能再钻了
I can't drill it again.
现在只能凭触觉了
I have to do it by touch.
我过不去 地铁把通道堵住了
I can't get through. The train's blocking the tunnel.
地铁从哪里上到地面？
Where does the Metro rail come above ground?
11大街和菲格大街交叉处
11th and Fig. Positions two and three,
在11大街与菲格大街交叉处碰头
meet at 11th and Figueroa and double back
然后再兜回到出事地点
to Hollywood and Highland.
快点
Hurry up!
请注意
Your attention please.
22次车行李
Baggage for train number 22
已在4号传送带
is now available at carousel number four.
22次车行李
Baggage for train number 22 is now available
at carousel number four.
我不行了，查理 斯特拉…
I can't do this,Charlie. Stella...
我不行了 我得用钻头管道镜之类的东西…
I can't do it-- I need a drill, a borescope,something.
我需要... 你不需要
I need to... -You don't need any of that.
快点，查理
Come on,Charlie.
嘿，你能行的
Hey,you can do this.
快点，快点
Come on,come on.
斯特拉
Slide.
快点，快点，快点
Come on,come on.
嘿，不想看看里面吗？
Hey. Don't you want to see what's inside?
当然想
Absolutely.
Napster 是
Napster. Yeah?
每排13个，高度4，深度4
1 3 across,four high,four deep.
总共208块金砖
That's,uh,208 bricks.
价值多少？
How much?
208乘以…
Oh. Uh,208 times...
2百70万
2.7... 2.7 million.
什么？
What?
不,是2千7百万
No,it's 27.
2千7百万
That's 27 million.
价值2千7百万
That's $27 million worth of gold.
!
Yeah!
老天保佑
Got the... holy spirit.
你们继续吧，这趟车真不错
You should get on it. It's a good train.
有什么感想，约翰？
What did you think,John?
2千7百万
27 million.
再说一次
Say it again.
2千7百万 再说一次
27 million. -Say it again.
再说一次 2千7百万
Say it again! -27 million.
再说一次
Say it again!
有两部摩托跟着我们
Two motorcycles on us,Charlie.
三部小车通过下水道 向东前往洛杉矶河
I've got three Minis in the storm drain heading east towards the L.A. River.
别让他们到达地面
Stop them before they get to the street.
该死
Shit!
喔!
Whoa!
到了
Here we go.
Whoo!
Whoa! Whoa!
开门
Open your door.
跟上，伙计们
Come on,guys,we're moving.
那里，那里
There,there,there,there, there,there.
嘿，快，快
Hey,come on,come on,look out.
快
Come on!
你要去哪？ 你要去哪？
Where you going? Where you going?
我要去对付史蒂夫 你们直接去联合车站
I'm going to take Steve. You guys go straight to Union Station.
我在那里和你们碰头
I'll meet you there.
跟住他，跟住他
Stay on him. Stay on him!
好的，查理 我给你开一条通道
Okay,Charlie,I'm opening up a spot on lower Grand.
我就知道是你，查理
I know it's you,Charlie.
下一个路口左转
T ake your next left.
跟的够紧，史蒂夫
Nice move,Steve.
出去
Get out!
出去 好的
Get out! -Okay.
你给我出去
I said get out!
那帮人在车上放了几部小车 对吧？
They got a bunch of cars in there,right?
迷你库柏斯？
Mini Coopers?
听着，哥们 我什么都不知道
Look,look,man...I don't know anything...
嘿，嘿，嘿，你别担心
Hey,don't worry about them.
如果你让我进去 我付你5千美元
I'll give you five grand you put me inside that car.
给你的女朋友买点好东西
Buy your girlfriend something nice.
来吧
Come on.
先付一半 等我下车再付另一半
Half now,half when you help me unload.
我对你深表敬佩，史蒂夫
I've got to hand it to you,Steve.
你可真是机关算尽
You actually played this one pretty smart.
真真假假的卡车 换了型号的保险箱
Decoy trucks... you switched safes.
直升飞机押运 这几手真是漂亮无比
The helicopter routine, I mean,that was pretty damn good.
只可惜金子已经归我 而你已一无所有
But now I've got the gold-- and you,you've got nothing.
我有这个
I got this.
少跟我废话 把金子还给我
So cut the crap, and give me my goddamn gold!
你是什么人？
Who the hell are you?
我叫马什科夫…
I am Mashkov...
你杀了我的表兄伊万
and you killed my cousin Yevhen.
你应该买份保险，史蒂夫
Got to have some insurance, Steve.
我到那里伊万已经死了
Yevhen was already dead when I got there.
我很遗憾，可是伊万常和很多 难缠的家伙打交道
I'm sorry about that, but Yevhen dealt with a lot of unsavory people.
这个家伙在玩弄你们
Now,this guy's trying to play you.
你真的…
You are right...
缺乏想像力
no imagination.
那边有很多金子
There's a lot of gold in there.
这里只有我们有枪 我们作笔好买卖
We're the only ones with guns. I'll make you a good deal.
我已经作完买卖了
I've already made my deal.
你想干什么？
What do you want?
你知道这和金子没有关系
You know this was never about the gold.
希望你晚上能睡得好，宝贝
Whatever helps you sleep at night,sweetheart.
婊子 查理！别这样
Bitch! Charlie! Come on,Charlie!
好了 干得好
Okay.
我喜欢
I love
等一下，等一下 等一下，等一下
Wait a minute Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
我付你们双倍的价 别枪杀我
Wait a minute. I'll double whatever he's giving you. Just don't shoot me.
别担心 我不会枪杀你的
Don't worry,I'm not going to shoot you.
我会带你到我的工场去
No,I'm going to take you to my workplace.
我的某些机器 你会很有兴趣的
I think you would be very interested in some of the machinery I use.
别这样
No,come on.
伙计们，我们碰一杯
Guys. I want to make a toast.
为了约翰・布里捷
To John Bridger,
最睿智的策划者
the most brilliant master planner of all.
父亲和朋友 为我父亲
Father and friend. To my dad.
为了约翰 为了约翰
To John
斯特拉说得对 这不是钱的问题
Stella was right. It wasn't about the money.
当然，无法阻止 这帮家伙去找乐子
Of course that didn't stop the guys from having a little bit of fun.
Money!
帅哥罗布买了阿斯顿马丁
Handsome Rob got his Aston Martin.
Get a good job with good pay...
找份好报酬的工作
He took it for a ride to break it in.
Money,it's a gas
Grab that cash with both hands and make a stash
将车当成泡妞的工具
He got off with a warning.
New car,caviar, four star daydream
左耳在西班牙北部 买下了梦寐以求的豪宅
Left Ear got his dream house in the south of Spain
有一间房专门放他的鞋
with a room just for his shoes.
Buenos dias.
Money,get back
莱尔最终登上杂志的封面
Lyle finally made the cover of Wired Magazine. I'm all right,Jack,keep your hands off of my stack
你真的是Napster？
Are you really the Napster?
Money!
是的，我就是
Yes,I am.
一直渴望的 音响也买回来了
And he got that kick-ass stereo he wanted.
你帮我听点东西，行吗？
Uh,would you listen to something for me?
音响带着巨大的喇叭 真能帮女人宽衣解带
With speakers so loud they'd blow a woman's clothes off.
I'm in the high-fidelity...
你能不能
If you would.
...first class traveling set
And I think I need a Lear jet
至于我
And me?
我采纳了 约翰・布里捷的建议
I took John Bridger's advice.
找到了与我共渡余生的人
I found somebody I want to spend the rest of my life with
我要和她永远相偎相依
and I'm gonna hold on to her forever.
Money!
It's a crime
Share it fairly,but don't take a slice of my pie
Money,so they say
Is the root of all evil today
But if you ask for a raise it's no surprise
They're giving none away
Away... away...
Away...
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer1342
Away... away...
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer